MUHAMMAD AKRAM AL BARI Software Engineer

Bandung, Indonesia | Phone: +6285157017311 | Email: <u>m.akram.bari@gmail.com</u> Linkedin: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/makramab/</u> | Website: <u>akramab.tech</u>

SUMMARY

An Informatics Engineering student at Institut Teknologi Bandung with multiple intern experiences, mainly in the Software Engineering department. Specialized in Backend Development using various tech stacks (Java, Python, PHP, Node.js, Go) and currently learning DevOps. Able to quickly adapt and learn in any different kind of teams.

EXPERIENCE

BFI (PT BFI Finance Indonesia Tbk) - Tangerang Selatan, Indonesia

Associate Backend Engineer (Dec 2022 - Now)

• Responsible for doing end-to-end development focusing on internal management tools SHOPEE (PT Shopee Indonesia) – Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Development Engineer Intern (Aug 2022 - Oct 2022)

- Responsible for implementing backend service to store and transform data from internal datamart
- Doing load testing by using wrk to simulate peak concurrent user situation

ICE HOUSE (PT ICE HOUSE) - Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Development Engineer Intern (May 2022 - Aug 2022)

- Using Go to make backend service
- Implementing cache by using Redis
- Make adjustment to some service by making it run concurrently to improve performance

ADVOTICS (PT ADVOTICS TEKNOLOGI GLOBAL) – Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Development Engineer Intern (Feb 2022 - Apr 2022)

- Improving existing API performance by implementing Reactive Programming for better concurrency.
- Using Java Spring Boot and MySQL as the main backend tech stack.

INFRASTRUCTURE SERVICE LAB PT. TELKOM INDONESIA – Bandung, Indonesia Backend Engineer (Jan 2022 - Nov 2022)

- Implementing Backend services using Node.js with Fastify
- Making configuration for automated CI/CD using Ansible
- Managing Kubernetes configuration for containerized deployment with Docker

BLIBLI.COM (PT GLOBAL DIGITAL NIAGA) - Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Development Engineer Intern (Sep 2021 - Jan 2022)

- Implementing new API features from various user stories.
- Using Java Spring Boot, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL, Redis as the main backend tech stack.
- Bug fixing and code refactoring while maintaining SOLID and clean code principle.

PROJECTS

COVID INFORMATIONS RETRIEVAL

- Source code could be viewed at: https://github.com/akramab/covid-information-retrieval
- Project that makes use of Indonesia Government Covid information public API.
- Made using Python FastAPI
- Containerized using Docker

EDUCATION

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG (2019 - present)

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering - GPA 3.39

SKILLS

- Backend Development (Java (Spring Boot), Python, PHP, Node.js, Go)
- Fast learner
- Critical thinking
- Team management
- Problem solving
- Data analytics
- Object Oriented Programming
- Kubernetes
- Ansible
- Redis
- FastAPI